[
    {
        "question": "Simple (সরল বাক্য) to Compound (যৌগিক বাক্য): He speaks like a leader.",
        "words": {
          "4": "he",
          "1": "leader",
          "3": "as",
          "2": "does",
          "5": "speaks",
          "6": "if",
          "7": "a",
          "8": "speaks",
          "9": "like"
        },
        "answers":[[4,5,3,7,1,2],4,8,3,7,1,2]
    },
    {
        "question": "Simple (সরল বাক্য) to Compound (যৌগিক বাক্য): Having finished his exercise he put away his books.",
        "words": {
          "4": "he",
          "1": "books",
          "3": "so",
          "2": "his",
          "5": "finishes",
          "6": "because",
          "7": "away",
          "8": "and",
          "9": "finished",
          "10": "put",
          "11": "exercise",
          "12": "his",
          "13": "as"
        },
        "answers":[[4,9,12,11,8,10,7,2,1],[4,9,2,11,8,10,7,12,1]]
    },
    {
        "question": "Compound (যৌগিক বাক্য) to Simple (সরল বাক্য): He is rich but he is unhappy.",
        "words": {
          "4": "he",
          "1": "in",
          "3": "of",
          "2": "is",
          "5": "but",
          "6": "unhappy",
          "7": "rich",
          "8": "spite",
          "9": "for",
          "10": "being",
          "11": "still"
        },
        "answers":[[1,8,3,10,7,4,2,6],[4,2,7,5,6]]
    },
    {
        "question": "Simple (সরল বাক্য) to Compound (যৌগিক বাক্য): He is too weak to walk.",
        "words": {
          "4": "he",
          "1": "walk",
          "3": "that",
          "2": "too",
          "5": "as",
          "6": "so",
          "7": "is",
          "8": "to",
          "9": "he",
          "10": "not",
          "11": "weak",
          "12": "can"
        },
        "answers":[[4,7,6,11,3,9,12,10,1]]
    },
    {
        "question": "Simple (সরল বাক্য) to Compound (যৌগিক বাক্য): Owing to bad luck he met with a bad accident on his birthday.",
        "words": {
          "4": "he",
          "1": "birthday",
          "3": "so",
          "2": "bad",
          "5": "unlucky",
          "6": "with",
          "7": "accident",
          "8": "he",
          "9": "therefore",
          "10": "met",
          "11": "on",
          "12": "in",
          "13": "for",
          "14": "and",
          "15": "his",
          "16": "was",
          "17": "a",
          "18": "being",
          "19": "as"
        },
        "answers":[[8,16,5,14,9,4,10,6,17,2,7,11,15,1],[4,16,5,14,9,8,10,6,17,2,7,11,15,1]]
     },
     {
        "question": "Compound (যৌগিক বাক্য) to Simple (সরল বাক্য): He is not only weak but also he is ill.",
        "words": {
          "4": "he",
          "1": "ill",
          "3": "weak",
          "2": "also",
          "5": "being",
          "6": "is",
          "7": "only",
          "8": "besides",
          "9": "not",
          "10": "but"
        },
        "answers":[[8,5,3,4,6,2,1],[4,6,9,7,3,10,2,1]]
    },
    {
        "question": "Simple (সরল বাক্য) to Compound (যৌগিক বাক্য): He is too poor to buy a car.",
        "words": {
          "4": "he",
          "1": "poor",
          "3": "as",
          "2": "a",
          "5": "buy",
          "6": "can",
          "7": "car",
          "8": "he is",
          "9": "very",
          "10": "that",
          "11": "not",
          "12": "so"
        },
        "answers":[[4,6,11,5,2,7,3,8,9,1],[8,12,1,10,4,6,11,5,2,7]]
    },
    {
        "question": "Simple (সরল বাক্য) to Compound (যৌগিক বাক্য): In spite of being my friend he did not help me.",
        "words": {
          "4": "he",
          "1": "friend",
          "3": "help",
          "2": "still",
          "5": "my",
          "6": "me",
          "7": "although",
          "8": "not",
          "9": "he is",
          "10": "but",
          "11": "did"
        },
        "answers":[[9,5,1,2,4,11,8,3,6],[7,9,5,1,4,11,8,3,6]]
    },
    {
        "question": "Compound (যৌগিক বাক্য) to Simple (সরল বাক্য): He went to a doctor and told of his illness.",
        "words": {
          "4": "doctor",
          "1": "illness",
          "3": "going",
          "2": "telling",
          "5": "he",
          "6": "a",
          "7": "went",
          "8": "told",
          "9": "to",
          "10": "his",
          "11": "of",
          "12": "then"
        },
        "answers":[[3,9,6,4,5,8,11,10,1]]
    },
    {
        "question": "Simple (সরল বাক্য) to Compound (যৌগিক বাক্য): In spite of being your friend I can not help you.",
        "words": {
          "4": "I am",
          "1": "I",
          "3": "you",
          "2": "your",
          "5": "help",
          "6": "friend",
          "7": "not",
          "8": "still",
          "9": "as",
          "10": "can",
          "11": "so",
          "12": "being"
        },
        "answers":[[4,2,6,8,1,10,7,5,3]]
    },
    {
        "question": "Simple (সরল বাক্য) to Compound (যৌগিক বাক্য): The man being very hungry ate too much.",
        "words": {
          "4": "he",
          "1": "man",
          "3": "hungry",
          "2": "much",
          "5": "the",
          "6": "as",
          "7": "so",
          "8": "too",
          "9": "very",
          "10": "ate",
          "11": "was",
          "12": "being",
          "13": "that"
        },
        "answers":[[5,1,11,9,3,7,4,10,8,2],[5,1,10,8,2,6,4,11,9,3],[5,1,11,7,3,13,4,10,8,2]]
    },
    {
        "question": "Compound (যৌগিক বাক্য) to Simple (সরল বাক্য): The children saw the giant and ran away.",
        "words": {
          "4": "giant",
          "1": "children",
          "3": "away",
          "2": "the",
          "5": "Seeing",
          "6": "they",
          "7": "the",
          "8": "ran",
          "9": "after",
          "10": "to"
        },
        "answers":[[5,7,4,2,1,8,3],[5,2,4,7,1,8,3]]
    },
    {
        "question": "Simple (সরল বাক্য) to Compound (যৌগিক বাক্য): Beside being intelligent he is also diligent.",
        "words": {
          "4": "he is",
          "1": "but",
          "3": "being",
          "2": "intelligent",
          "5": "diligent",
          "6": "not",
          "7": "also",
          "8": "he is",
          "9": "only"
        },
        "answers":[[4,6,9,2,1,7,8,5],[8,6,9,2,1,7,4,5]]
    },
    {
        "question": "Simple (সরল বাক্য) to Compound (যৌগিক বাক্য): Being dissatisfied he resigned from his position.",
        "words": {
          "4": "he",
          "1": "his",
          "3": "he",
          "2": "from",
          "5": "as",
          "6": "so",
          "7": "dissatisfied",
          "8": "resigned",
          "9": "position",
          "10": "was"
        },
        "answers":[[4,10,7,6,3,8,2,1,9],[3,10,7,6,4,8,2,1,9]]
    },
    {
        "question": "Simple (সরল বাক্য) to Compound (যৌগিক বাক্য): In spite of being poor he is happy.",
        "words": {
          "4": "he is",
          "1": "but",
          "3": "happy",
          "2": "poor",
          "5": "he-is",
          "6": "being"
        },
        "answers":[[4,2,1,5,3]]
    }
]